Here's the Firewood Office's dressing room.
这里便是劈柴处的易容间
Song Jin,
宋锦
pick a couple of costumes.
挑两套衣服
Sir.
爷
Miss Qiu Yan, try this on.
秋嫣姑娘 你穿这个吧
Let me see.
让我看看
I want a different one.
我要换一套
I want this one.
我要这套
You want me to play a servant boy?
让我当小厮
You just want to order me around.
又想对我呼来喝去
Your Lordship wants to reenact the scene at Heming Building.
大人想要重演鹤鸣楼一幕
Lord Liang, do remember
梁大人请记住
that we're working together.
我们现在是合作关系
But Miss Qiu Yan,
秋嫣姑娘
you and His Lordship
你跟爷去的可是
are going to Wanyan House.
万艳楼啊
She's right.
她说得对
It's a joint action.
合作嘛
She can dress up anyhow she wants.
愿意扮演什么都行
Song Jin,
宋锦
stick a mustache on her.
帮她贴上胡子
No need. I'll do it myself.
不用 我自己来
I know how to stick it.
我自己会贴
I've watched operas before.
我看过唱戏的
Help yourself, then.
那您自便
Song Jin, leave her alone.
宋锦 别理她了
Help me get changed.
更衣
Sure.
好嘞
Song Jin, what do you think?
宋锦 怎么样
I didn't expect Miss Qiu
没想到秋姑娘
to look pretty in men's clothes.
穿上男装的样子还挺俊俏的呢
Lord Liang.
梁大人
Childish.
幼稚
You're here.
您来了
Did everything go well?
一切都顺利吧
He's dead.
人已经死了
It's all thanks for your timely notice.
这次是多亏你通告及时啊
Since he's already dead,
既然人已经死了
shouldn't you honor the promise
那您看是不是把之前许诺的
you made me before?
兑现给老朽啊
I know
我知道
you're talking about Miss Shaoyao.
你说的是芍药姑娘
But she can't go with you.
但她不能跟你走
Why?
那是为何呀
Because
因为
I never planned to let you live!
我就没打算留你活口
Sir, please come in.
大爷里面请
Come and take a look.
来看看呀
Come in.
来嘛
What are you doing?
干什么
You better remember
你给我记住
that you're a man now.
你现在是个男人
It smells so nice.
好香啊
Why didn't you send anyone to inform Qin Xuan?
为什么不找人告诉秦暄
If he knows, he'll get worried
他若得知 定不放心
and will come along.
就会跟来
Then the scope of our target will be wider.
那咱们的目标就更大
Besides,
况且
I don't want him to take risks for me.
我不愿意他为我涉险
You're thoughtful of him.
你对他倒是思虑周全
Since I'm relying on him,
我既是攀龙附凤之人
I can't let him be in danger.
我当然不能让我的金主涉险啊
Listen.
我告诉你
After entering Wanyan House,
进了万艳楼之后
I won't let you be in any danger
只要你事事听我吩咐
as long as you follow what I say.
便不会让你身处险境
Song Jin.
宋锦
Yes, my lord.
在
We'll set six hours as the time limit.
三个时辰为限
If I don't come out by then, come and get me.
要是我没出来 就直接进来
Yes, my lord.
是
Have you made up your mind?
想好了吗
Do you really want to go inside?
真的要进去吗
Since we're already here, so say no more.
都已到此 何须赘言
Then remember your role
那你要记住你自己的身份
and play it to the end.
咬了牙都要给我演下去
Of course.
那是自然
Sir, come on in.
大爷来呀
Miss!
小娘子
Let's go back to the room.
咱们回房
I've caught you.
抓住了吧
Where do you think you're running off to?
我看你往哪儿跑
Wait for me!
你等会儿我
So what do you think?
怎么样
Do you like it here?
喜欢吗
You still have time to leave.
现在要走还来得及
I won't.
我不
Hello, Sirs. You must be new here.
二位爷 新来的吧
You don't look familiar at all.
看着面生啊
Is this your first time to Wanyan House?
可是第一次来咱们万艳楼
My friend and I are in the tea business.
我们两位兄弟做茶叶生意
We don't always come to the Capital.
难得进京
Wanyan House's fame spreads far and wide.
听闻万艳楼艳名远扬
So we came out of admiration.
慕名前来
How should I address you, Sirs?
二位爷如何称呼啊
My last name is Song.
我姓宋
My friend's last name is Qin.
这位小公子姓秦
The reputation of every girl here
我们这儿的姑娘啊
precedes them.
个个人如其名
Every minute spent is precious.
所谓春宵一刻值千金
Whether it's precious depends
值不值千金
after we take a look at them.
我们挑挑人再说了
Of course.
得嘞
Girls, come on out!
姑娘们都出来了
We're looking for Miss Shaoyao.
咱们找的那姑娘不就是叫芍药吗
Why didn't you just ask for her?
你干吗不直说呀
We're not regular customers here.
我们又不是熟客
It'll be too obvious if we ask for her directly.
单刀直入 未免太刻意了
So what?
这有何不可
Who's in charge here now?
这种地方听你的还是听我的
You.
听你的
You're a regular. Of course, I have to go your way.
你是熟客 当然听你的
What are you mumbling about?
你说什么
Madam, this friend of mine
妈妈 我们这位小兄弟啊
is still a young lad.
还是一个雏儿
He's shy.
面皮儿薄
Then I'll arrange a girl
那我定给秦爷
who can give great care to Mr. Qin.
寻个体贴入微的姑娘
He has had a different taste from others since he was young.
他自幼眼光啊 异于常人
Are there any special ones?
有没有更特别一些的
Special ones?
特别
Oh, we do!
有 有 有
Wait, just wait here.
你等着啊 等着
- Wait here. - Thank you, Madam.
等着 辛苦妈妈了
You can just do it yourself.
这种事你自己上就好了
Why did you get me involved?
你拉着我干什么
Behave yourself, Qin.
老实点 秦兄
If you were content with playing the role of my servant boy,
你若安心做我的小厮
you wouldn't get a turn in this matter.
这种事情还轮不到你
But you picked this role,
不过身份是你自己挑的
and we entered as friends.
称兄道弟地进来
Are you going to be the upright one and let me be the immoral one?
难不成你还想独善其身
My name is Xiahe.
奴家夏荷
Sir, am I soft enough?
爷 夏荷软不软和
Sir, don't go.
爷 你别走呀
Pick me. I'm the most voluptuous one here.
你选我 我最丰满了
Qin, calm down.
秦兄 别着急
You're scaring her.
你吓到别人了
Pick me.
选我
Help me.
救我
(Please help me.)
求求你了 救我
- Madam. - Don't go. Pick me.
妈妈 别走 选我
I get it now.
我现在总算明白了
You're looking down on us because we're inexperienced.
你是瞧不起我们没见过世面
You don't even bring us the good ones.
有好货都不拿上来
Sirs, why do you say that?
二位爷何出此言哪
Before I came here, my friend told me
我来之前有朋友告诉我
that Miss Shaoyao of Wanyan House was a charming person.
万艳楼的芍药姑娘颇有意趣
Why did you send this type of girl
你怎么上这种
and not Miss Shaoyao to us?
唯独芍药姑娘不上来见我们
Shaoyao?
芍药
You have no taste at all.
有眼无珠
I don't mean to do that.
不是老身藏着掖着
Shaoyao made some mistakes previously.
这芍药前儿犯了事
It's against the rule for her to entertain the guests.
若是见客 不合规矩
I don't care if it's against the rule.
不管合不合规矩
I must see Shaoyao today.
我今天必须要见到芍药
All right, then.
那行吧
I'll make the exception for Mr. Qin today.
我今天啊 就为秦爷破回例
Follow me.
跟我走吧
Sirs, this way, please.
二位爷这边请
She pretended to be reluctant
方才她故作赶客
to extort more money.
无非是为了讹钱
You were pretty generous there.
我说你倒是大方啊
You can just get reimbursement from the public purse.
你回头找公家报销便是
Don't tell me Firewood Office can't afford
你们劈柴处
to pay for this public spending?
不会连这点公费都出不起吧
Who says we can claim it from the public purse?
谁说这银子可以找公家报销啊
That was my salary!
我告诉你 那是我的俸禄
I'm so sorry! I'm so sorry!
小的该死 小的该死
Madam, have mercy on me!
妈妈饶命
You're still careless.
还是这么不长
You darn girl,
你个死丫头
I'm going to teach you a lesson after this.
待会儿不揭了你的皮
I apologize.
恩公莫怪
This girl is always this clumsy.
这丫头啊 素来笨手笨脚的
Never mind.
算了 算了
I'll help her compensate
这套茶具啊
for this tea set.
我帮她赔了
Take this.
拿着
Take it. Why aren't you thanking him?
拿着吧 还不谢恩
Thank you, Sirs. Thank you, Sirs.
谢过二位爷 谢过二位爷
Let's go, Madam.
走吧 妈妈
All right.
好 好 好
Sirs, this way, please.
二位爷 这边请
How do you still have money?
你怎么还有钱哪
Liu, stop cleaning.
老刘 擦什么擦
Go help out in the front.
快去前面帮忙
Yes, Madam.
是 是 是
Sirs, this way, please.
二位爷 里边请
Sirs, come in, please.
二位爷 这边请
Greetings, Sirs.
芍药拜见二位恩公
You have no idea
二位有所不知
I've been confined for days.
芍药已被禁足多日
It's all thanks to you for getting me out.
今日全靠二位恩公搭救
Qin,
兄弟
I thought you always try to be funny.
平时不是挺不正经的吗
Miss Shaoyao,
来来来 芍药姑娘
no need to rush.
我们不急不急
Let's put your clothes back on.
我们先把衣服穿上
My friend is shy by nature.
我这位兄弟呢 生性腼腆
How about we have a nice talk first?
我们不如先聊聊天
So you prefer something artistic.
原来二位是想雅玩啊
I wonder if you want to discuss poetry
那不知是想聊诗书呢
or enjoy some pleasure of...
还是风月
Don't you think talking about pleasures
你说在风月场聊风月事
at a brothel is unnecessary?
岂不是多此一举
As for poetry,
至于诗书
don't you think it'll be even more awkward?
不会显得更尴尬吗
I don't think you spent money here
那二位爷花钱来这儿
just to hear me talk about this city, right?
总不会想听我介绍这京城风貌吧
Miss Shaoyao, tell me about yourself.
芍药姑娘不如来聊聊你自己呢
You're so naughty.
讨厌
Nothing is interesting about me.
我有什么可聊的
Then have you met
那芍药姑娘有没有见过
some interesting people?
那些有趣的人
What do you mean by interesting guests?
什么有趣的客人啊
I find both of you to be interesting.
我看二位就挺有趣的
Have you met
芍药姑娘有没有遇到那些
the ones you find annoying, then?
让你非常厌烦的人呢
Let's drink, Sirs.
来 二位爷
Never mind about this guy.
这位兄弟就算了
Let's enjoy this ourselves.
我们自己来
What a thing to say.
瞧您说的
They're all my paying customers.
都是些给钱的金主
No matter how ridiculous they behaved,
再怎么下流胡闹
it's still not that annoying.
也不至于说厌烦
If you must mention the annoying ones,
要非说烦吧
I must say it's customers who don't pay.
就是那种一毛不拔的客人吧
There are such stingy customers?
还有这等小气的客人
Can't you decline them?
那芍药姑娘推托不见不行吗
Here.
来
Madam Chen would chase
一般这种客人啊
these kinds of customers away.
妈妈也就打发了
There's only one person
只是有一个人
who doesn't pay.
虽然次次来赖账
Yet, I can't refuse him.
我却不能推托
It's because he's Tao Zhugong's subordinate.
只因为他是陶朱公的手下
Then...
那
Tao Zhugong is...
陶朱公
Wanyan House's owner.
就是万艳楼的老板
Speaking of Tao Zhugong,
说起这个陶朱公啊
no one has seen his face
估计除了陈妈妈
other than Madam Chen.
没有人见过他的正脸
No one even knows his name.
更没有人知道他到底叫什么
That's why we called him Tao Zhugong
所以姐妹们才会私底下
in private.
管他叫陶朱公的
Your boss sure
那你们老板还真的是一个
is a mysterious person.
很神秘的人
I just don't understand
我只是想不通
why he would hire such an inferior subordinate.
他怎么会请那么下三烂的手下
He looks like a refugee fleeing from famine.
简直就像逃荒的流民一样
So have you given him
那芍药姑娘有没有
anything before?
送过他什么东西
Why would I give anything to that kind of person?
我怎么会送东西给那种人
But I just remembered
不过我突然想起
the nameplate I hung at the main hall a few days ago
早几日我挂在大堂的铭牌
went missing once.
曾丢过一次
Now I think of it,
现在想想
he must be the one who took it.
十有八九就是他给顺走的
Then...
那
Then
那芍药姑娘
when was the last time he saw you?
他最后一次见你是什么时候啊
Speaking of that,
说来也巧了
I ran into him when I came
方才我过来找二位爷时
to meet up with you.
恰巧碰见他
But he looked like
不过看他样子
he was on his way to see Tao Zhugong.
应该是直接去找陶朱公了
Then did he...
那他
You don't look like businessmen.
我看二位爷不像是生意人
You look like you're from the government office.
更像是衙役的呢
Don't run!
你 你别跑
I find those two a bit strange.
我总觉得方才那两个人有些古怪
Watch Shaoyao's room.
你给我盯紧芍药的屋子
Make sure not to cause any trouble.
别给我捅出什么娄子来
Yes, Madam.
明白了
Other than talking about someone else,
与其听其他人的故事
how about doing
倒不如现在就跟芍药一起
something more interesting
做一些
with me?
更有意思的事情
Sir, don't be nervous.
小爷不用紧张
The incense of Wanyan House has a powerful aphrodisiac effect.
这万艳楼的熏香极富催情之效
Whether they're a regular
无论是常步万艳之客
or a newcomer to Wanyan House,
还是初到此地的客人
I can assure you won't be disappointed
我都保证能让你不失所望
and go home with satisfaction.
满意而归
You... You have none!
你 你没有
Can't you make your move faster?
你就不能早一点出招
You don't need to interfere when I make my move.
我什么时候出招不用你来管
She's not waking up after this, right?
她今天不会醒了吧
Don't worry.
放心吧
She won't be awake before daybreak.
她天亮之前都醒不了
Who's there?
什么人
Sirs, Madam Chen instructed me
两位爷 妈妈着我给芍药姑娘
to send a contraceptive concoction to Miss Shaoyao.
送一碗红花汤
She doesn't want it.
她不想喝
According to Wanyan House's rules,
万艳楼的规矩
every girl needs to drink this.
每一位姑娘都要喝
Sir.
爷
Don't get in my way.
别耽误爷时间
Get lost.
滚
Yes, Sir.
好的 爷
It's hot in here.
怎么这么热呀
Madam, I've checked.
妈妈 我去看过了
There's nothing fishy about those two new faces.
那两个生面孔没什么异常
They're having fun with Shaoyao at this moment.
此刻正与芍药
Looks like I was oversensitive.
看来是我多心了
But it's better to be safe than sorry.
不过这个关头小心一点总是没错
Receive Official Yao who's waiting outside,
你去把外面等着的姚知事
and bring him to the backyard.
给我带到后院吧
Yes, Madam.
是
Have some water.
来 喝口水
What's wrong with me?
我这是怎么了
The fragrance in this room is too strong.
屋子里香薰太盛
What were you trying to do to me?
你方才想要对我做些什么
You were the one who wanted to do something to me.
方才分明是你要对我做什么
Don't worry.
你放心
Even if I have the urge,
我就是有心放浪
I won't pick you.
也不会找你
Adjust your clothes.
快穿衣服吧
We have work to do.
还有正事要办
By the way,
对了
I won't tell anyone about what happened just now,
刚才的事情我不会告诉任何人
especially Qin Xuan.
尤其是秦暄
Thanks but no thanks.
谢大人好意
We're here to investigate a case.
你我同行是为了办案
Even you tell him, he'll understand.
你就是告诉秦暄 他也能理解
Since the incense in this room has such a miraculous effect,
这屋里的熏香既然有如此奇效
why didn't it work on you?
那为什么似乎对大人不起作用呢
I've learned martial arts since I was young.
我从小习武
How can I be compared with ordinary people?
岂能和常人相提并论
I thought you were suffering from an unspeakable disease.
我还以为这大人有什么隐疾呢
I dare you to say that again.
你再说一遍
I was just kidding.
开玩笑而已
If Shaoyao is telling the truth,
这个芍药若是所言非虚
the old man who monitored Xiao Tie is Tao Zhugong's subordinate.
监视肖铁的老头是陶朱公的手下
Then Tao Zhugong
那这个陶朱公
is likely the main culprit in printing the fake notes.
很有可能是印制假银票的首犯
Then Wanyan House
那这个万艳楼
is a cover.
其实是一个幌子
So it's convenient for the officials and nobles to buy fake notes.
方便达官贵人前来买卖假银票
This is only our presumption.
这只是你我判断
Next, we need to catch them red-handed.
下一步就需要人赃俱获
Since this is where they exchange the fake notes,
这既是假银票的交易之地
there must be a warehouse too.
那一定还有库存
Xiao Tie's murderer must be here, then.
想必杀害肖铁的凶手就在于此
Wait.
等等
You've made many mistakes the moment you entered Wanyan House.
从迈进万艳楼开始你就破绽百出
If you didn't rush to spend a lot of money to see Shaoyao,
方才若不是你赶着花重金见芍药
Chen wouldn't be suspicious
老鸨也不会起疑心
to send someone to check on us.
让人来听墙角
It's my first time to a place like this.
我是第一次来这种地方
I don't have any experience.
没有经验
But nothing went wrong.
但终归是有惊无险啊
The criminals couldn't care less about your experience.
犯人不会管你有没有经验
If you want to continue the investigation with me,
还想跟我继续查下去
you must follow my orders.
就必须事事听我的
If you want me to follow your orders,
若是想让我听你的
you must be reasonable first.
那自得是你有道理
Drink slowly.
慢点喝
Come here.
来
Pour it.
倒上
Have you seen Chen?
见到老鸨了吗
It's the attendant.
是那个跟班
What is it?
怎么了
I know that person.
那个人我认识
He's the administrative clerk from the Council of State.
是参政院的知事
Come on.
走
Let's follow him.
跟上他
Madam, Official Yao has arrived.
妈妈 姚大人到了
Official Yao, it's been a while.
姚大人 好久不见
Madam Chen, how are you?
陈妈妈别来无恙啊
Go back and watch the brothel.
你回去看场子吧
Yes, Madam.
是
I have cash notes worth 500 taels
这里是五百两银票
for 15 pieces of yours.
换你们的十五张
Official Yao, this won't do.
姚大人 这可不行啊
You should know Wanyan House's rules.
万艳楼的规矩您应该都懂
First, we don't accept cash because it's hard to transfer.
一不收现银 不便转移
Second, we don't accept cash notes because it's hard to keep.
二不收银票 不好保存
You should bring something more decent.
您呀 还是拿点像样的东西吧
This is our Yao family's heirloom.
这可是我们姚家的传家之宝
If it's put out in the market,
放到世面上
its value is no less than 800 taels.
不会低于八百两
Madam Chen, stay. I know the way out.
陈妈妈留步 姚某认得路
This is it.
就是它
Let's go back and inform Song Jin
那咱们赶紧回去通知宋锦
and shut Wanyan House down immediately.
即刻封了万艳楼
We mustn't.
不可
With only these few fake notes,
就凭这几张假银票
if they deny it until the end
如果他们死咬不开口
or be killed like Xiao Tie,
或者像肖铁一样被人杀人灭口
they'll only be charged
他们最多也就落个
with circulating fake notes at most.
流通假银票的罪名
So you want to find Tao Zhugong first?
所以你要先找到陶朱公
Why do you think I come here in person, then?
要不我为什么亲自跑这一趟
To catch small fry?
只为抓几只小鱼小虾吗
If you ask me,
要我说呀
since there's a secret passage,
既是这里有暗道
we should let Song Jin confiscate it before doing anything.
还是先让宋锦前来查抄再说
After all, it's too risky
不然仅凭咱们两个人
with just the two of us.
未免太过涉险
Do you still want to investigate?
你还查不查
Why are you holding to me so tightly?
我说你抓那么紧干吗呢
It's too dark. I can't see.
黑 我看不见
You're scared, right?
怂了吧
You're the only one who knows what the murderer looks like.
只有你见过杀手那张脸
If we want to capture the murderer,
我们想要缉拿真凶啊
we must bring you along.
必须带着你
You said that yourself.
是你自己说的
Let go of me.
放手
You're so annoying.
烦死了
I had no idea
真看不出来
there's such a maze
这万艳楼底下四通八达
under Wanyan House.
宛如迷宫隧道
This must be a cavern
这应该是自然形成的地下坑洞
naturally formed underground.
基础上修砌而成的
That's why the route is not straight and complex.
所以才会如此迂回复杂
Tao Zhugong probably picked
陶朱公也许就是看中
this cavern
这片自然坑洞
and built Wanyan House above it.
才会在上面兴建万艳楼
You're pretty smart
我说你倒挺聪明的
to get yourself a candle.
给自己照亮
Do you think
这地儿
you can handle this place without me?
没有我 你一个人能行吗
What?
干吗
We're already here. No need to act anymore.
都走到这儿了 还伪装什么呀
How overconfident can you be?
真不知道哪来的自信
Let's go.
走吧
A... A dead body.
尸 尸体
It's him?
是他
The old back alley rogue.
流民巷的白发老头
He was silenced like Xiao Tie.
被人灭口 跟肖铁一样
Looks like the assassin is here.
看来刺客就在此地
Follow me.
跟我来
We have less than 200 pieces left.
还剩不到两百张
The Duke and Minister Lv
明晚国公爷和吕尚书
will send their men over here tonight.
就会派人过来
We should be able to sell all of it.
应该能全数卖出
Good. After tonight,
好 明晚一过呀
destroy everything here. Leave nothing behind.
这里面全部销毁 一样不留
I think those lads
我估摸着用不了几天
(Yao)
劈柴处那帮家伙呀
this place in a few days.
就该找上门来了
What about the corpse?
那尸体怎么办
Do I need to teach you again?
这还用我教你吗
Tao Zhugong, calm down. I'll take care of it.
陶朱公息怒 我一定料理干净
As for these boxes,
至于这些箱子呢
you don't have to worry about them.
你也不用操心了
I'll send some men over
明天晚上我会派人过来
to move these boxes out tomorrow night.
把这些箱子全部运走
By the way,
对了
tell the girls to leave the day after tomorrow.
后天一早 把姐妹们全部遣散
Just tell them
就跟她们说呀
that Tao Zhugong has left the city
这个陶朱公前两天哪
and headed down south a couple of days ago.
就已经离开京城往南边去了
If the girls know,
姑娘们知道了
those from Firewood Office will know too.
劈柴处的人就自然知道了
I'd like to see where those from Firewood Office
我倒要看看劈柴处怎么去南面
can capture a "Tao Zhugong" down south.
抓一个陶朱公回来
That person must be Tao Zhugong.
那个人应该就是陶朱公吧
They wouldn't have expected
他们应该没有料到
that we were already at Wanyan House.
我们这么快就找到了万艳楼
These three look like martial artists.
这三人的身形啊 都是习武之人
See
你看看
if the assassin is one of them.
他们之中有没有那个刺客
I
我
can't see clearly.
看不清啊
Who's there?
什么人
Run.
走
Hide.
躲进去
Call for help!
快去叫人
All right.
好
Don't think about running.
别想跑
Come back to Firewood Office with us.
跟我们去劈柴处
Liang Yi!
梁翊
Qiu Yan, come on!
秋嫣 走
Wait for me.
等等我
I'll go this way.
我走这边
Come back here.
你回来 回
Wait a minute.
不对
Didn't we use this way just now?
这一段咱们是不是走过啊
Looks like we went in circles.
看来我们又兜回来了
Let's try this way.
走这边试试
The man who hid the crossbow just now
刚才那人藏有臂弩
must be the man who assassinated Xiao Tie.
想必是刺杀肖铁之人
Yet, you didn't recognize him.
你却没有认出来
It was a dangerous situation
刚才情急之下
and too dim for me to see clearly.
灯光灰暗 我没看清
Qiu Yan, I'll ask you one more time.
秋嫣 我再问你一遍
Did you see the assassin's face?
你究竟有没有看清刺客的真面目
Fine.
好
I admit.
我承认
I lied to you.
我的确骗了你
But if I didn't lie to you,
可若非如此
you wouldn't bring me along for the investigation.
你肯定不会带我查案的
No wonder you didn't want to come down with me.
难怪你刚刚迟迟不愿随我下来
It wasn't because you were scared.
原来不是害怕
You were worried your lies would be exposed.
是担心自己的谎言被揭穿
Qiu Yan, do you know
秋嫣 你知不知道
what's the crime is for obstructing Firewood Office's investigation?
干涉劈柴处办案是什么罪
I did lie to you.
我是骗了大人
But didn't you lie to me
但你不也为了自己的目的
for your own purpose too?
骗过我吗
If you want to judge,
若一定要算
we're both
我与大人
the same.
也就是彼此彼此
Do you really think
我说你是不是以为
I'll go easy on you
不管你怎么胡闹
no matter how ridiculous you behaved because of Qin Xuan?
我都会看在秦暄面上饶了你
All right. Then kill me now.
好 那就请大人现在把我杀了吧
There's no one else in this dark tunnel anyway.
反正在这个地下暗道也无人目睹
You can just tell everyone
大人大可以对外宣称
that I was killed by the bad guys.
我是被贼人所杀
All right.
好
If you act willfully again,
你再自作主张
I'm going to ignore you.
我可不会再管你
Have you forgotten what I said at the entrance just now?
我说你在门口没听懂我说的话吗
There's something odd about this paper.
这纸里面有古怪
I'd be a fool to believe you again.
我要再信你我就傻
What's wrong with you?
你就什么呀
I'm not lying this time.
我真的没骗你
There's an odd smell on these papers.
这些纸上有一股奇怪的味道
You can smell it.
不信你闻
This is the smell of Hongzhen Sect's Incense of Worship.
这是弘真门敬神香的气味
Hongzhen Sect?
弘真门
The smell may be faint.
这味道虽然薄弱
But the smell will be covered when it meets ink.
但一旦遇上油墨就会被覆盖住
The smell of Incense of Worship is unique.
敬神香的气味很特别
There's no mistake.
我不会搞错
In that case,
照这么说
the Ministry of Revenue is not the only one supplying the fake notes.
假钞的纸张不只是户部提供
Hongzhen Sect may be involved in this too.
弘真门很有可能参与其中
This case is far more complicated
此案牵涉之深
than I'd imagined.
远远超过我的想象
Let me check
我再找找看
to see if there are other clues.
还有没有其他的线索
You?
是你
Are you working for Tao Zhugong?
你是陶朱公的人吗
No! I'm not!
不是 不是 不是
Sirs, you've got it all wrong.
二位官爷你们误会了
Why are you here?
你怎么会在这里
I...
我
Speak.
快说
I'm here to steal the cash notes.
我是来偷银票的
Why?
到底怎么回事
I'm Ping'er.
我叫萍儿
My father and I work at Wanyan House.
和爹爹都在万艳楼里讨生计
He works as a porter at the gatehouse.
他是迎门的门房
Father.
爹
Liu, stop cleaning.
老刘 擦什么擦
Go help out in the front.
快去前面帮忙
Yes, Madam.
是 是 是
Sirs, this way, please.
二位爷 里边请
My father has always been in poor health.
我爹爹素来身体不好
He needs medicine to nurse his health.
一直需要服药调理
But our monthly wages
可我二人每月所得
are only several coins.
不过几吊铜板
So I can only take the risk
萍儿只好铤而走险
to sell the things I stole.
偷拿别人的东西去卖
How did you end up stealing from this place?
你怎么会偷到这里来
At first, I stole from the customers.
一开始是偷客人的东西
Then I start stealing from Madam Chen.
后来偷陈妈妈的
I found this place by accident.
无意中发现这里
So I'd come in here to steal
我便隔三差五
a few fake notes every few days.
跑进来偷几张假银票
They didn't notice anything until now
因为每次只拿一两张
because I only stole one or two fake notes at a time.
所以不曾被他们察觉
Sirs, please spare me
求二位官爷
for the sake of me being filial
看在萍儿一片孝心的份上
to my father.
饶了萍儿
If I go to prison,
萍儿要是坐牢了
my father won't live anymore.
爹爹也活不下去了
That makes sense.
这倒也说得通啊
Come, get up and talk to us.
来来来 你快起来 起来说
All right. Since you said,
好 依你这么说
you came here many times.
你进出这里那么多次
So you must be familiar with the tunnels here.
对这里的暗道应该很熟悉
So do you know
那你可知道
where's is the other exit of the tunnel?
地道的另一个出口在哪儿
I think so.
大概知道
I've never been there.
只是我不曾去过
Tell me, and I'll let you go.
告诉我 我便饶了你
Watch your steps.
小心脚下
It's right here.
就是这儿
Please come with me.
请随我来
Looks like you're right.
看来你猜得没错
Hongzhen Sect is indeed involved.
这果然跟弘真门有关
This is bad.
不好
What?
怎么了
This is the Imperial Park.
这是禁苑
Imperial Park?
禁苑
His Majesty cultivates to be immortal, reveres the Grand Preceptor.
圣上修仙 尊崇国师弘真上人
So His Majesty bestowed a piece of land in the suburb of the Capital city
在京郊赏赐一片土地
to build Hongzhen Holy Palace.
用于建造弘真圣宫
Besides His Majesty and the Masters of Hongzhen Sect,
除了圣上和弘真门高阶
outsiders are forbidden to enter.
外人严禁入内
That's why it's called the Imperial Park.
所以称之为禁苑
I came here once for a ritual with His Majesty last year.
去年我和圣上祭祀来过一次
In that case,
这么说来
the one behind Tao Zhugong
陶朱公背后的大庄家
is the Grand Preceptor himself.
就是国师本人
If that's the case,
若真是如此
this is a shocking case that can shake the country's foundation.
那便是动摇国本的惊天大案
We can't stay here.
此地不宜久留
We must leave now.
我们快走
Who's there?
什么人
Liang Yi from Firewood Office requests an audience with the Grand Preceptor.
劈柴处检校使梁翊求见国师
Based on what you said,
依梁大人所言
Wanyan House's tunnel leads directly to the Imperial Park.
这万艳楼竟然直通我禁苑
Yes.
正是
If I wasn't after the villain,
若不是追赶歹人至此
I wouldn't have dared to break into the Imperial Park
梁翊也不敢擅闯禁苑
and cause a disturbance to you.
惊扰国师清修
I hope you can lift the restriction here
希望国师可以立即开放禁苑
and let the Firewood Office search the place.
让劈柴处的人进来搜查
Outrageous! The Imperial Park is a holy place of the Hongzhen Sect.
大胆 禁苑乃我弘真门圣地
If you use force to solve this,
如若兵戈相见
it'll definitely anger the heavens, and wrath will be upon us!
必然冒犯天神 招来天谴
Stop trying to trick us with the so-called wrath from heaven.
什么天神天谴 装神弄鬼的
You're clearly afraid that this scandal
国师分明就是害怕丑事
will be exposed to everyone.
暴露在日光之下
How dare you. Apologize to the Grand Preceptor now.
放肆 还不快给国师赔礼
Please don't take this to heart. I failed to teach her well.
国师莫怪 梁翊管教不严
I know very well
我的人自然清楚
that you're not involved in this matter.
此事与国师无关
I'm just worried that your disciple may do this behind your back.
只怕是门徒背着国师 牵涉其中
If it's because several ungrateful disciples
如若是因为几个不知好歹的手下
affect His Majesty's trust in you,
影响圣上对您的信任
I'll find it unfair to you.
在下真是替国师感到不值
Miss, get up first.
姑娘 你先起来吧
Lord Liang, stop putting an act.
梁大人 你不用在我面前演戏
If someone from Hongzhen Sect does evil,
若弘真门真有人为非作歹
I'll never tolerate it if I find out.
待我查出 绝不姑息
I'm afraid
只怕是
someone deliberately plants evidence to set me up.
现在有人故意栽赃陷害吧
I truly admire your righteousness.
国师深明大义 梁翊钦佩
If you do the investigation yourself,
只是自己查自己
you'll be said to harbor the villains
无论结果是如何
no matter the outcome.
您都会落个包庇结党之名
Lord Liang, are you doubting me?
梁大人 你这是在怀疑我吗
I dare not.
不敢
It's simple if you want to convince the public.
国师想要服众 其实很简单
The suspect who escaped here is injured in the leg.
逃入禁苑的嫌犯腿上有伤
If you gather everyone from the Imperial Park
现只要将禁苑的所有人
and let us check one by one,
都召集在一处 让我们一一查验
you can prove Hongzhen Sect's innocence then.
便可还弘真门一个清白
What a joke.
笑话
Why do I need to prove our innocence to Firewood Office?
我何须向劈柴处自证清白
What if the Firewood Office insists on investigating?
如果劈柴处执意要查呢
Then I can only report to His Majesty
那我只能禀明圣上
that you broke into the Imperial Park with motives.
你们夜闯禁苑 居心叵测
Then we'll let His Majesty make a choice between you and me.
让圣上在你我之间做个抉择
Master, I saw Xuanjing looking flustered
师父 我方才巡视时
and going into the meditation room
见玄静身受刀伤
with injury while patrolling.
神情慌张溜进静思房
I asked him about it,
我上前询问
but he didn't answer me.
他一概不答
I saw him acting suspiciously.
我见他形迹可疑
Who's this?
这人谁啊
So I took him here to see you.
因此押他来见师父
He's the head of Hongzhen Sect, Lingzheng.
弘真门的掌教灵正
The second person under the Grand Preceptor.
国师之下的第二人
Bring him here.
押上来
He's the one we were after.
我们追的就是此人
Xuanjing,
玄静
are you really involved
你当真涉足了
in the fake notes business at Wanyan House?
万艳楼假银票的勾当
I'll take responsibility for what I did.
一人做事一人当
You can punish me according to the sect's regulations.
拿门规惩处便是
How dare you do such a shameful thing?
你竟然干出如此有辱教门之事
How do you want me to face His Majesty in the future?
你让我日后有何颜面追随圣上
Grand Preceptor, calm down.
国师息怒
There are many disciples in Hongzhen Sect.
弘真门弟子众多
It's hard to say there are no bad apples.
难保有一两个蛀虫啊
I'm sure His Majesty won't blame you.
想必圣上也不会过多怪罪
I have no intention to publicize this case either.
此案梁某也无意张扬
I only need to bring the suspect back to Firewood Office
只需要将人犯带回劈柴处
for questioning.
细细审问
Lord Liang, you're truly transparent in handling things.
还是梁大人做事通透
Lingzheng,
灵正
hand Xuanjing to Lord Liang.
把玄静交给梁大人
Grand Preceptor, I'll take my leave, then.
国师 那梁翊先告退了
What...
这
Lord Liang, you're truly skilled.
梁大人身手不凡
If I don't use some tricks,
不动点心思
how can I easily have you under control?
怎么能轻而易举控制梁大人呢
Looks like you're the mastermind.
看来你才是幕后之人
Lord Liang, your deduction is right.
梁大人推断有理
You solve cases with great speed.
办案神速
However,
不过
I never expected
我竟没想到
that you'd force me
你逼得我
to do it myself!
不得不亲自动手
Lingzheng,
灵正
are you out of your mind?
你疯了
How dare you point your sword at me?
你居然拿剑指着我
Shut your damn mouth!
闭上你的臭嘴
Master, you focus on cultivation with all your heart and soul
师父 你一心玄修
that you didn't know Imperial Park has fallen into my hands.
却不知道禁苑早已落入我手
The current emperor is nearing his end.
当今圣上已经日薄西山
How many years more he can still dote on you?
还能宠你几年
When the Crown Prince succeeds the throne,
太子登基
Hongzhen Sect will be the first he comes after!
第一个倒霉的就是我们弘真门
The fake notes business
买卖假银票之财
is to bribe the Crown Prince's trusted follower
我就是拿来打点太子的亲信
to give leeway to Hongzhen Sect.
为我们弘真门留一活路
What's so funny, Lord Liang?
梁大人笑什么
I laughed because you have a well-devised plan.
我笑掌教一盘好棋 运筹帷幄
But if the Grand Preceptor and I
可是如果梁某今日同国师
die at the Imperial Park together,
一起死在禁苑
how will you explain it to His Majesty?
你如何和圣上交代
You're right about that, Lord Liang.
梁大人所言极是
You're the emperor's favorite now.
梁大人是当今圣上的红人
If things didn't come to this point,
假若事不到此
I didn't have to do this.
我也不必这样
How about you end him for me
要不梁大人替我了结了他
and put the fake notes business on him.
把买卖假银票之事栽赃于他
When I become the Grand Preceptor,
待我当上了国师
I'll definitely repay you.
我必定报答梁大人
You underestimate me too much.
你也太小瞧梁某了
Why should I listen to you?
我为何听你的
Of course, you won't listen to me.
梁大人当然不会听我的
Then your beautiful friend
不过你身边的红颜知己
will have to die here today.
今天可要魂断于此了
Fine.
好
Give me one night.
给我一晚时间
I shall wait for your news.
等梁大人消息